<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Eudaimonia</title>
    <description>Long Form Jekyll theme built with SASS / COMPASS / SUSY</description>
    <link>http://brianmaierjr.github.com/long-haul/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://brianmaierjr.github.com/long-haul/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 06:19:59 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 06:19:59 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.0.0</generator>
    
      
      <item>
        <title>3 years later</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;To start off with, let me first say I am very excited for starting this blog up again. It’s been 3 years overdue and I think I’m in a good spot mentally to be doing this kind of thing again. It won’t be with the same kind of self jack-off righteousness and make-myself-sound-so-driven garbage I was writing before. I hope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To begin things off, I’ll leave a note to my future self:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Figure out how to package this stupid blog into a docker container or something so that if I ever need to set this up again, then I won’t have to jump through these hoops… This might be the first time I’ve tried back-compatibalizing a 3-4 year old project with the latest builds of tooling. Needless to say, it was a humbling experience for your local hackerman. I’d thought the WSL use at work had helped me out a lot (and I’m sure it helped me some), but this setup was
definitely way too difficult. I started at around 2am. It’s now 6:09am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.1) Note to self: always check whether you’re installing something locally or globally when using packages on mac… I just installed two versions of ruby, one via brew and one via ruby version manager (rvm), and they didn’t see each other’s builds. SO, rvm -v gave 2.6.5, and ruby -v gave 2.6.3, and the gems were all criss crossed looking for each other. It wasn’t a fun time. I actually got halfway into installing GatsbyJS, which is node based, and fortunately for me I gave this Jekyll site
another chance before going down that rabbit hole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Visit some old posts and examples to get a primer on md, so you can format your posts well with the &lt;em&gt;bolds&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;italics&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) I’m going to take a different direction with this blog going forward. I’d like to use it more as a journal so I can look back and reflect on my thoughts in the future. It’s a difficult balance to find when journaling - you want to write enough so that you have enough to think about when looking back, but you don’t want to write too much either. The fluff really makes it hard to sift through your thoughts well. Maybe a twice per week cadence, or a once per week cadence would work well. I’d
mainly like to journal my progress towards endeavours in music, health, and career.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;To start off with, let me first say I am very excited for starting this blog up again. It’s been 3 years overdue and I think I’m in a good spot mentally to be doing this kind of thing again. It won’t be with the same kind of self jack-off righteousness and make-myself-sound-so-driven garbage I was writing before. I hope.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://brianmaierjr.github.com/long-haul/blog/nexter-goals/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://brianmaierjr.github.com/long-haul/blog/nexter-goals/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Next Goals</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In the last post, I found that explicitly writing out the consequences of achieving a goal (and particularly what sacrifices you must make) helps tremendously prepare you for taking action. In a sense, you envision yourself before, during, and after the process, so that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a) Nothing takes you by surprise (during the process)
b) Your eyes stay focused on the goal (the end of the process)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I’m going to do that again for another set of goals I hope to accomplish by Christmas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These were goals I’d previously set but failed to meet. I’m now here to buckle down and get to business. The next three months will be intense on self improvement in many facets of my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Everyday, I’m going to work on something that improves myself. I’ve more or less been building healthy habits for the past couple of months, but they don’t seem to stick. There must be something fundamentally wrong (such as a lack of internalization) with the way I’m approaching these goals. To be more specific about this point, I’m going to improve in three fields particularly:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.1) Technically - work hard and smart at work, do some extra (personal?) stuff at home. Could be coding, or simply tackling stimulating problems in mathematics, physics, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To accomplish this, I’ll have to sacrifice time wasted surfing the web, and also learn to take extended periods of time without a “break” (read: game of league/overwatch). It’ll be tough, and I don’t think it’ll get any easier over the month. Nevertheless, I will power through and treat this as an exercise for my tenacity. I will not track the number of problems I solve, because that’s about as superficial as you can get in terms of learning metrics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.2) Culturally - Read!!!! Everyday!!! There is no excuse to this. I’ve a terrible habit of leaving things half done. This is properly exemplified by the 30 or so books that I have sitting between 10 - 80% on my kindle. Yes, I’ve dropped books even though I was at 80%. For some reason, I don’t find the enjoyment in seeing things to the end. Maybe it’s because I’m a consumerist millenial that’s always chasing the next quickest dopamine release, but I hate the fact that I do things half assedly. I’ll be trying my best to finish things through to the end. This will allow me to appreciate things in their entirety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be completely honest, the only thing I have to sacrfice here is time. (read: game of league/overwatch). Half an hour a day is NOT hard, and reading should not feel burdensome. You’re learning, and you’re intaking information. Helps with visualization, writing, and focus management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll feel extremely sleepy about 3-4 pages in, but I recognize this and will &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; let myself stop after 3 short minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.3) Communicating - I did poorly in my recent interview with Facebook. While I solved two out of three problems presented to me, I’m fairly confident that it was the ones I DID solve that lost me the opportunity, as opposed to the one I did NOT solve. This is because I truly struggle to clearly articulate my thoughts. It’s a big mess in my head and I fail to put anything coherent in front of my interviewer. I’ll try to explain one complex topic a week to one of my friends who don’t know about the topic. I think I’ll have the most fun for this one, as it doubles for a chance to reconnect with some old friends, and try out some &lt;em&gt;Win Friends and Influence People&lt;/em&gt; tactics from Dale Carnegie’s one of a kind book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a side report of my previous weightloss goals:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Current weight:175.8
Target: 170.0
Deadline: Nov 30.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lost more than expected, though I’m pretty sure the majority of my weight lost was waterweight. This, plus the fact that I started my log at the highest point I’d measured in a while (probably also due to water weight).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-endofpostsignaturehere&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;In the last post, I found that explicitly writing out the consequences of achieving a goal (and particularly what sacrifices you must make) helps tremendously prepare you for taking action. In a sense, you envision yourself before, during, and after the process, so that:&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://brianmaierjr.github.com/long-haul/blog/next-goals/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://brianmaierjr.github.com/long-haul/blog/next-goals/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>More on Goalsetting</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My friend said something interesting that caught my attention the other day. We were talking about our career choices and plans for the coming few years, which is very natural for people in their 20’s. Specifically, what he mentioned was the &lt;em&gt;sacrifices&lt;/em&gt; we would have to make for each possible career we could choose. Now, for some reason, this stuck to me really hard over the next couple of days. For some reason, I had never truly thought about the consequences of success, though I’d understood that success was difficult, and entailed many hard days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was interesting, because I’ve failed to accomplish a lot of my goals in the past. When thinking about it, I can confidently say that whilst setting my goals, I didn’t realize what I had to sacrifice in order to properly accomplish what I’d set out to do. I tried to have everything - to have my cake and eat it too. An easy example is that I tried to go on a low-carb diet without understanding that the sacrifices I would have to make are enduring feelings of hunger, many long tiring days, and a general lack of energy throughout. These things are by nature characteristic of the low-carb diet (at least when you start out). Yet, by being unaware that they were sacrifices I had to make, I was constantly looking for ways around the inconveniences that the diet brought. I made excuses to “eat carbs on days I exercies,” or “allow milk because it’s healthy.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you don’t understand the sacrifices you need to make to advance toward you try to find cheats that offset the hard work, pain, and effort required to improve yourself. Yet, if there was truly an easy way around weight loss, why would anyone ever be fat?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hard work is meant to be hard. You can make it easy on yourself and do easy work, but you’ll also stagnate exactly where you are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, my goal for the summer was weight loss. Although I’ve shed some weight off, I’m nowhere near where I’d planned to be. So, as of right now, I’m going to explicitly state what my goals are, and what sacrifices I’ll be making.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Current Weight: 185.6lb 
Target Weight: 170lb
Time: By the start of December (3 months, 12 weeks. Approx 1.3lb/week)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fundamentally weight loss is about increasing exercise and decreasing calories. It’s that simple. There are several sacrifices that I’ll have to make in order to succeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) I’ll have to properly track my calories, even though it’s a huge hassle. This means that after every snack or meal, I’ll have to pull out my phone and properly track the foods that I’ve eaten.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) When I’m out of calories for the day, I MUST REFUSE ALL OFFERS AND OPPORTUNITIES FOR FOOD. I’ll also have to endure whatever hunger I may have afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) There are days where I’m extremely tired, and will want to eat a ton of food at breakfast, lunch, and dinner. On these days, I will also have to endure the hunger and tiredness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) I’ll also have to spend some time to develop useful eye-ball metrics for food quantities. Such as translating my fist into a number of grams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) I will have to endure tiring training days at Muay Thai. I will have to endure tiring days at the gym. I &lt;em&gt;cannot&lt;/em&gt; not go.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;My friend said something interesting that caught my attention the other day. We were talking about our career choices and plans for the coming few years, which is very natural for people in their 20’s. Specifically, what he mentioned was the &lt;em&gt;sacrifices&lt;/em&gt; we would have to make for each possible career we could choose. Now, for some reason, this stuck to me really hard over the next couple of days. For some reason, I had never truly thought about the consequences of success, though I’d understood that success was difficult, and entailed many hard days.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://brianmaierjr.github.com/long-haul/blog/more-on-goalsetting/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://brianmaierjr.github.com/long-haul/blog/more-on-goalsetting/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>On being driven and the short-term goal</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I want to write down some thoughts on ‘motivation’ and the short term goal. I dispose/despell the idea that motivation is necessary in self-improvement or success, and expand on the short-term goal that I overlooked for a long time. Let’s get into it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;motivation&quot;&gt;Motivation.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My thoughts on motivation is that it’s bullshit - in the sense that it helps no one get anywhere. Logically, of motivation was a key factor for inspiring change in people, then shouldn’t the world be filled with many-times more successful people, sheerly by audience count of motivational speakers? I’ll tell you, from first hand experience, that motivational speeches are exactly what they are - extremely motivating. You feel like electricity afterwards, and that you can conquer the world. You go home, research whatever it is you want to do on the internet, and make some phonecalls. Some things go ask you expected, some don’t, but that’s okay, because you’re motivated and you’ll push through it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two days later, you have a get-together with friends that extends late into the night. “Come for another hour at X’s place! It’ll be fun!” Sure, why not, you thought, given that it’s a Friday and that you’ve done good work for the week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As expected, you wake up around noon-time Saturday feeling hungry and tired. You retreat home and relax, and slowly recuperate from your antics last night. You look at the clock and realize that it’s 9pm now. Where did the day go? It’s too late to work seriously on the project I was so motivated about now, I can do that tomorrow. It’d be worse if I screwed up my work schedule for Monday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sunday comes along and you realize your house is a mess. I just relaxed yesterday, so of course I’m going to have a messy room today. Work starts again tomorrow so I’ll be too tired in the evening - better do it now! You finish cleaning at 3pm, and havent’ eaten yet. Time for lunch!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could go on with this forever, but I’m sure you get the idea. This story has played out in my life way more times than I’d like to admit. But such is the result of ‘motivation’: not much. Motivation is but fleeting, and does not push us to improve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly, if you take any successful person, and you analyze the amount of time he/she put into his/her profession/career/passion, you’ll realize that they are &lt;em&gt;driven&lt;/em&gt;, not motivated. The successful are the dedicated, driven individuals who can muster their strengths at 5am in the morning to get their workout in while everyone else sleeps. What motivation do you feel at 5am?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t be motivated, be driven. Be disciplined, and continue to push yourself &lt;strong&gt;especially&lt;/strong&gt; when it’s boring, bothersome, and hard. If it was easy, everyone would do it, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-short-term-goal&quot;&gt;The short term goal&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is something I’ve recently found some enjoyment playing around with. The great thing about the short-term goal is that it enables us to feel accomplishment when we work towards our long-term goals. The key aspect is to ensure your short-term goals are &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;QUANTITATIVELY MEASURABLE.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; This is because long-term goals, while important, are often difficult to track. You want to become a professional photographer and you just got into an arts-oriented university with a fantastic photography program. How close are you to your goal? 10% there? 50%? It’s impossible to say for sure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you instead, use a short-term goal that assists your long-term goal, like “I’m going to spend 3 hours a week of my own time outside of class to practice what we learned.” You can track this, and measure how close/far from your short term goal. You can then pivot, adjust, and modify your goals as you see fit. The trick is to keep it measurable so you are working in manageable chunks for yourself. Make sure you push yourself too though!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, I have a long-term goal of getting to the next level of Muay Thai by the next testing season, and then HOPEFULLY a demo fight or amateur fight by the end of the PEY year. However, this isn’t helpful in my day-to-day training. I’ve chosen instead to set incremental, short-term goals on my workout and technique during training.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A current short-term goal I have is to properly get down the technique of a swing (roundhouse) kick. To achieve this, I will square up with a heavy-bag after every class, and throw 15 orthodox and 15 southpaw swingkicks where technique is as tight as possible. I will focus on technique, and work on power later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My ability to accomplish this goal or not will give me insightful improvement feedback on what I need to work on next. If I fail, I will analyze why I failed: poor balance? Do more core-work; not flexible enough? stretch every day; etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a last note for this section, I want to talk about avoiding the pitfall of erroneous tracking. The point of the measureable short-term goal is that it helps you analyze how you are doing in a certain aspect of your long-term goal. This means that you want to track the &lt;strong&gt;numbers that matter&lt;/strong&gt;. Numbers that matter are numbers that you can control. For example, if you’re interested in losing weight, your short term goal should NOT be to lose X amount of weight by Y date. This is beyond your control. You need to instead track the number of calories you eat, and check your weight to see if your caloric goals are sufficient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;exiting-note&quot;&gt;exiting note&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To tie the two concepts together, for those wondering how they link together, short-term goals helps you develop discipline and an internal drive to push harder. Stay driven, people!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I want to write down some thoughts on ‘motivation’ and the short term goal. I dispose/despell the idea that motivation is necessary in self-improvement or success, and expand on the short-term goal that I overlooked for a long time. Let’s get into it!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://brianmaierjr.github.com/long-haul/blog/short-term-vs-long-term/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://brianmaierjr.github.com/long-haul/blog/short-term-vs-long-term/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>First blog post: All about work</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been meaning to make a blog and start posting for quite some time but kept putting it off. Summer 2016 marks the beginning of new things so here we go. In this post, I’ll primarily be talking about the first two months of my PEY.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The University of Toronto has a fantastic internship opportunity known as the Professional Experience Year (PEY) program. The PEY program is a 12-16 month internship that gives students a true feel of working at a company or startup. Unlike traditional 3-4 month internships, students engage their work longer and get a deeper understanding and appreciation (or disdain) of their chosen profession. This also gives students the option to focus, re-adjust, or 180 their course choices for 4th year, so that what they learn better reflects what they wish to do in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for me, I’ve chosen to work at a company called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dacgroup.com&quot;&gt;DAC Group&lt;/a&gt; as a software developer. DAC stands for Directory Advertising Consultants, and in layman terms, my company offers digital marketing services from end to end (google ad to transaction page). DAC Group and has taken a highly digitalized stance, fully embracing the information age. I work full-stack development for one of the applications (services provided) along with one other PEY student and a team of 4 full-time software engineers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my time at DAC group, I’ve been a part of a major release and production deployment that DAC Group has launched. I didn’t read my non-disclosure agreement too closely when I signed, so I’m really not sure what can and cannot say. However, several things have become very apparent for me as I look forward towards the next 20+ years of my career:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Software is only a tool. It can be used to create services, platforms, and networks, but by itself it is worthless.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For a well-paying software career that grows as you age, you’ll need to either enter upper management or get into big companies in the Si Valley.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;1-software-is-only-a-tool&quot;&gt;1. &lt;em&gt;Software is only a tool&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While point 1 is very obvious, I found it to be quite a turning point in how I see my future, especially in conjunction with point 3. In stock trading, people are often told to “find their own edge.” This makes intuitive sense, because if there was an edge everyone had, it would no longer be an edge. For example, a software engineer may find his edge in analyzing technology trends and placing his money in promising small to medium sized companies. This edge is unique to him (and other software engineers) because only his understanding of technology allows him to make educated investments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarily, if you want to create something meaningful and new with software, your ‘edge’ over competitors lies in the knowledge advantage that you hold (or lack) with respect to the thing you want to develop. The mentality should not be “I know software, so I’ll make something,” but rather “I want to make something, so I’ll learn software.” This means that anyone hoping to escape software in the future and do their own thing better have a damn good idea about what service they’re trying to provide rather than the software technologies they plan to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;2-get-into-upper-management-or-silicon-valley&quot;&gt;2. &lt;em&gt;Get into upper management or Silicon Valley&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note that this point is only interesting if money is a primary concern for your career. Many people choose to prioritize things like lifestyle and location over money, and so would argue this point heavily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps getting into the states is fine, but it seems that Canadian software engineers experience extremely limited growth over their careers. In canada, you’d be lucky to break the 90k/annum mark (pre tax). While that sounds pretty good, and is certainly enough to live your life comfortably, I think that it’d be selling yourself short for any sort of seasoned software engineer after 20+ years of experience. For the following numbers I’m about to provide, you can verify by a quick google search that I’m in the correct ball-park amounts. Example &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.payscale.com/research/CA/Job=Software_Engineer_%2F_Developer_%2F_Programmer/Salary&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.glassdoor.ca/Salaries/toronto-software-engineer-salary-SRCH_IL.0,7_IM976_KO8,25.htm?countryRedirect=true&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.payscale.com/research/US/Job=Software_Engineer/Salary&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most software engineers enter the scene (in Canada) at anywhere of 45k - 60k per annum, and will cap to about 90k, where they will either switch fields or enter management. This 50% growth over &lt;em&gt;the course of a career&lt;/em&gt; means that near the end of your career, you are monetarily 1.5x your value when you began. In reality, you may be producing 10 - 15 times more value for your employer. In the field of software development, there is a popular notion of the “10X engineer,” who is regarded as a highly productive engineer that is 10 times more productive than his/her peers. This doesn’t mean that the 10x engineer will solve a problem in 3 minutes when it would take his peers 30 minutes. Instead, the 10x engineer solves the &lt;em&gt;correct&lt;/em&gt; problem, and thus alleviates the need to revisit the problem at a later time. Additionally, his code is clean and understandable, which saves incoming new engineers time to understand the current code base. You can read more about the 10x engineer &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quora.com/Are-there-engineers-who-are-not-10x-but-100-or-1000x-as-productive-as-the-average&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, but the bottom line is that your productivity and value is not reflected in your salary as you become a better and better software engineer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowing this, I focus every day to write code that is understandable, reusable, and dynamic. I think hard about every problem that I solve, and make sure that I target the core of the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been meaning to make a blog and start posting for quite some time but kept putting it off. Summer 2016 marks the beginning of new things so here we go. In this post, I’ll primarily be talking about the first two months of my PEY.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://brianmaierjr.github.com/long-haul/blog/first-post/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://brianmaierjr.github.com/long-haul/blog/first-post/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
